<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ShoReason</title>
    <description>Welcome to the musings and ramblings of a life learner. My interest range from technology to business, design and data science. I hope you experience at least one &#39;Kairos&#39; moment while you are here.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 19:09:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 19:09:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>TQN on Rich Dad, Poor Dad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of saying I can’t afford it, think/ask “How can I afford it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secrets of Rich Dad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-1-the-rich-dont-work-for-money-learn-how-to-let-money-work-for-you&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 1&lt;/strong&gt; The rich don’t work for money (learn how to let money work for you)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-2-dont-let-emotions-fear-or-greed-drive-your-decisions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 2&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let emotions (fear or greed) drive your decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fear&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ignorance&lt;/strong&gt; are the bigger causes of poverty
Ignorance about money drives greed and fear. Learn to use your emotions to think not think with your emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need financial literacy to be rich. Elements of financial literacy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accounting&lt;/em&gt; (Ability to read and understand fiancial statements)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investment&lt;/em&gt; (money making strategies)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding of &lt;em&gt;Markets&lt;/em&gt; (Science of supply and demand. Does an investment makes sense based on the current market?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Law&lt;/em&gt; (Understanding of tax advantages of a corporattion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know the difference between an &lt;em&gt;asset&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;liability&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rich acquire assets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poor only have expenses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Middle Class acquire liabilities thinking they are assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset&lt;/strong&gt; - Puts money in your pocket
&lt;strong&gt;Liability&lt;/strong&gt; - Takes money out of your pocket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More money only accentuates the cash flow pattern running in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we really need a lsson on is not how to make money but rather how to spend it (financial aptitude)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wealth = if I stopped working today, how many days will I survice (the measure of the cash flow from the asset column vs expenses). This is different from &lt;strong&gt;net worth&lt;/strong&gt; = assets  - liabilties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goal 1 - Get asset cash flow to match expense
Goal 2 - Get enough excess cash flow from asset to reinvest in assests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-3-mind-your-own-business-build-and-keep-your-asset-column&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 3&lt;/strong&gt; Mind your own Business (Build and keep your asset column)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rich focus on their balance statement, everyone else on their income statement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The business you are in is different from your profession&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real Assets
+ Businesses that don’t require my presence (I own them but they are run or managed by other people) - If I have to work there it;s not my business it’s my job
+ Stocks
+ Bonds
+ Mutual Funds
+ Income generating Real Estate
+ Royalties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acquire assets you love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich buy luxury last, poor and middle class buy luxury first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-4-own-a-corporation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 4&lt;/strong&gt; Own a Corporation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-5-the-rich-invent-money&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 5&lt;/strong&gt; The Rich Invent Money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial Literacy requires technical knowledge and courage. Smarts and guts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to take risks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to understand what business you are invested in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-6-work-to-learn-not-to-earn-not-for-money&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret 6&lt;/strong&gt; Work to Learn not to Earn (not for money)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things to learn: Accounting, Investing, Marketing, Sales, Negotiation and Law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to know a little about a lot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seek work, position or role more for what you will learn than what you will earn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education is more valuable than money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management Skills for success
+ Management of cash flow
+ Management of systems (including self and time with family)
+ Management of people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surround yourself with people smarter than you are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use assets not credit to buy luxuries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have Mentors or Icons you follow/imitate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;George Soros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peter Lynch (How does he invest?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carl Icahn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steve Cohen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jim Rogers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Warren Buffett (What does he invest in?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donald Trump (How does he negotiate?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A stock investment strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest in stock at valued price&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When it goes up take out original amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave increase in the rest of investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 16:58:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/08/tqn-on-rich-dad-poor-dad.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/08/tqn-on-rich-dad-poor-dad.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TQN on the Riddle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Include domain experts and novices when solving a problem (existing knowledge and ignorance are useful in creativity)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend time really understanding &lt;strong&gt;the problem&lt;/strong&gt; and identify existing attempts at solving it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t ignore tangential information. A good way to leave your subconsious working on a problem is to do the ff to see if the answer comes to you while you sleep or after taking a mental break&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave sentences unfininshed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write down a question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, write down a problem statement/question before going to bed (one entence). Think about it for a few mins then sleep. When you wake up write down what ideas come immediately to mind. Sample question: “Why is checking into a hotel not as simple as renting a car as far as self service goes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain knowledge and expertise are key to novel ideas when combined with irrelevant information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep helps you consolidate information to long term memory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativitiy requires&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building domain knowldge in an area&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curiosity in unrelated areas (be deliberate about exploring the edges such as seeking out experiences you ordinarily wouldn’t)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On innovation and Breaking rules:
You can’t &lt;em&gt;intentionally&lt;/em&gt; break the rules if you don’t know the rules. It’s also not about being naive to the rules but rather ignoring the rules and convention.
You need to be able to identify and challenge beliefs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Creativity Framework or Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curiosity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constraints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conventions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-curiosity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Curiosity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mood related influences for creativity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Positivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mood/Emotional state changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The future belongs not to those who create ideas but to those who make viable”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“History not reality crowns the first movers”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to nuture Curiosity through Observation and Experimentaion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question “What if …?” is the birthplace of creativity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-constraints&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Constraints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on constraints. Observe - “What can’t they do?” not “What do they need?” 
Understand “What are they unable to do?”
Being first is not as important as being relevant
Innovation goes beyond having access to resources, displaying resourcesfulness is more important. That your team does not have enough budget may not be a viable excuse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behavioral and resource constrainrs spur creativity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is essential to develop the skill to be able to identify and define problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Varying Definitions of the word ‘Problem’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Source of difficulty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State of difficulty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Question raised for consideration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in a state that is different from where you want to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical reactions to Problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discomfort&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frustration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Curiosity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rethinking problems not as a source of difficulty but rather as a series of questions can spark creativity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-connections&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Connections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Eureka moments and exposing ambiguity:
Identifying prevailing biases and then challenge the truths with “What If?”
Wy are doors rectangular? Why do cars have 4 wheels?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to deal with constraints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;change how you solve the problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;change how you preceive the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what business you’re in, the only way to get a non customer to be a customer is to start a new conversation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help make unrelated connections, keep unsolved problems top of your mind through unconscious processing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help with unexplored connections between existing information (previous knowledge), write down unsolved problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increased specialization is great for efficeincy but not creativity and innovation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation is the business of cross boundary thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make time to think and reflect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think broadly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn to think outside of the box think broadly, read broadly and live broadly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, be a T or F shaped individual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memory, attention and perception are a big deal in learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-conventions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Conventions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To break out of &lt;strong&gt;functional fixedness&lt;/strong&gt; think about conventions that exist in a domain and explore each piece trying to figure out what would happen if th e opposite of each piece is instead the norm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To innovate in a new domain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write down the success factors of existing players&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note down customer wants, needs and constraints which they are not able to articulate
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Determine why they buy and choose not to buy, as much as you try to understand what they want&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explore the micro factors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;form unrelated connections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What analogies exist for similar problems in a different domain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make list of constraints and conventions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t focus on innovation, focus on solving real problems”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become a problem solver not innovator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure is a great wat to eliminate wrong solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure reduces the number of possible solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success could be dangerous because it might hold back search for a better solution hindering continuous improivements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the general idea that you could have creative codes,or approaches/broad framework on how to solve problems. If you find a creative code that helps you continue to innovate make use of it (at least until it is no longer true)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 06:38:59 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/09/tqn-on-the-riddle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/09/tqn-on-the-riddle.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 2016 Challenge : Kafka or MQTT for Messaging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Messaging is a critical aspect to any distributed architecture. Even more vital in modern architecture is that you need a way to decouple actors or systems within your ecosystem. Pub/Sub is one model that allows you achieve this. In tthis model one component in your environment broadcasts/ publishes a message which can then be consumed/subscribed to by by 1 or more components or consumers. The compoment that acts as the middle man in this model is called a broker, which is what MQTT and Kafka do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MQTT&lt;/strong&gt; is a protocol made for light weight messages. It is great for situations where low bandwidth is a constraint and with about 2 bytes header size it is well suited for small devices like an Arduino and Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-characteristics-of-mqtt&quot;&gt;Key Characteristics of MQTT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightweight (2byte overhead per message)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to parse for computers (length prefixed length)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broker keeps track of client state&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guarantees message delivery through retries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security (usr/pwd over TLS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamic topics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Runs on TCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kafka&lt;/strong&gt; is essentially a distributed commit log. Kafka’s claim to fame is its support for high throuhput and message durability even at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-characteristics-of-kafka&quot;&gt;Key Characteristics of Kafka&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distributed Log aggregator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client keeps track of what messages it has processed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meant for server side environments (server to server)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Static topics (topic - static, key - dynamic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common features across both solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both brokers for pub/sub&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decouple consumers from producers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offer measure of reliability (QoS 1, 2 &amp;amp;3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both solutions address the key needs I have for messaging so which did I choose. Well I chose both. The essential thing about these two solutions is that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MQTT is suited for dumb clients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kafka for smart clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my ecosystem the sensors at the edge capturing electricty usage, temperature and humidity readings etc  are simply observing an event and transmitting light weight data. In this case I use MQTT to pipe in their data. Kafka comes into the picture as the main broker through which all collected data are streamed over to the ELK Stack. I forsee Kafka playing a much bigger role when I pull in data at rest or batch data for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working with these two to really grasp where they fit, but so far I feel comfortable about how they are used. I did come across some material on the web around problems with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VoTclkxSago&quot;&gt;Scaling MQTT&lt;/a&gt;. Scale is not something I’m worried about around the edge, so MQTT does what I need. Kafka helps me manage the scale I have at the heart of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other choice I had to make recently was how to persist the data, which I’ll cover in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 13:17:28 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/04/messaging-kafka-vs-mqtt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/04/messaging-kafka-vs-mqtt.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 2016 Challenge : The Foundation (1 Min Read)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technically I started work on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoreason.github.io/2016/03/31/my-2016-challenge-1-min-read.html&quot;&gt;2016 challenge&lt;/a&gt; late 2015. The goal remains to have something tangible done as the year progresses. This brings me to the foundation of all I intend to build: The Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Software Engineer, I deal with Architecture decisions daily. Making best guesses on future design and ruminating on past bad decisions. In the Agile landscape I have come to terms with that fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://shoreason.wordpress.com/2014/02/16/did-someone-lose-architectures-invite-to-the-agile-party/?frame-nonce=2e4aab6523&amp;amp;preview=true&amp;amp;iframe=true&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/a&gt; is really where you land and the initial key decisions are around mitigating risks. How much time one puts in upfront architecture decision depends on what you are building: A shed or a skyscraper. In my case I choose to land somewhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typically advocate for a factor of 3 to account for the smallest unit of complexity. In this first round I was focused more on simplicity which meant a single node and single broker where possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current tech-stack includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MQTT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ELK Stack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cassandra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Linux boxes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming language choice -  C, Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensor Peripherals (Efergy Electricity Monitor and R820 Tuner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/EfergyDataPipeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;Data Pipeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my view from Kibana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kibanaEfergyScreenShot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kibana Visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 17:02:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/01/my-2016-challenge-the-foundation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/01/my-2016-challenge-the-foundation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 2016 Challenge (1 Min Read)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/vodafone_de/17768794394/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Smart Home: Das digitale Wohnzimmer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/306/17768794394_d4dcb320cc_k.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; alt=&quot;Smart Home: Das digitale Wohnzimmer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Mark Zuckerberg recently shared his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10102577175875681&quot;&gt;2016 challenge&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently, he takes on something new every year and it got me inspired.  Making focus a priority is a goal of mine moving forward in life and it seems well fitting to articulate what had been brooding in my mind to take on in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge in 2016 is to make my home sentient. I spend a lot of a quality time in my home and it only makes sense for me to enrich the experience. I’m not sure what this end point really looks like - Jarvis from Iron Man? Maybe not but, I know my interest is to start with capturing key information around my home like power usage and internet bandwidth usage to be more aware of what’s happening in the home. Measure such things as temperature, humidity and presence detection. This is also so my home can intelligently respond to my living experience. Essentially, me learn about my home and my home learn more about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already started some work around power usage monitoring and will be sharing what I have learned as well as my journey to make a smart home. Yes, that’s the word. I expect this will have varying elements of IOT, Big Data, Machine Learning and Deep Learning. All areas I have been looking forward to take a deep dive into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to write a monthly blog reflecting on my journey in between more technical blogs highlighting what I have actually done. You are welcome to tag along.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 21:38:30 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/31/my-2016-challenge-1-min-read.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/31/my-2016-challenge-1-min-read.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 Reading List</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Art of Action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Becoming a Technical Leader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jack Welch and the GE Way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Riddle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Launch Pad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Drucker lectures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The SW airlines way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Brain Advantage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 Years to 7 Figures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat the Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 16:58:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/25/2016-reading-list.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/25/2016-reading-list.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
